A Finding Aid to the Federal Art Project, Photographic Division Collection, circa 1920-1965, bulk 1935-1942, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Artist Files, circa 1920-1965; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 9.6 Linear feet Boxes 1-24
  - Velonis, Anthony, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Vidar, Frede, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Vogel, Joseph, circa 1937-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Von Minckwitz, Katharine, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Von Wicht, John, circa 1938-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Vrachopoulos, Demetrios, 1937-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Vuchinich, Vuk, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Vukovic, Marko, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Wahl, Albert, 1938-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - Wahl, Theodore, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Walkowitz, Abraham, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Walsh, Barnard, circa 1938-circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - Walter, Joseph, circa 1937-circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - Warren, Wilbert, circa 1937-circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - Warsager, Hyman, 1937-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 42)
  - Warthoe, Christian, circa 1937-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 43)
  - Watrous, James, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 44)
  - Webb, Albert J., circa 1936-circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 45)
  - Weidhaas, Ted, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 46)
  - Wein, Albert, 1938-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 47)
  - Wein, Elsie, 1937-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 48)
  - Weinstock, Carol, 1938-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 49)
  - Weinstock, Saul, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 50)
  - Weiss, Hugo, 1937-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 51)
  - Weiss, Julius, circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 52)
  - Weiss, Reginald, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 53)
  - Weissbuch, Oscar, 1936-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 54)
  - Weller, Paul, 1938-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Weschler, Anita, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Wessels, Glenn, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - West, Pennerton, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Wheeler, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Wheelock, Warren, circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - White, Ruth, circa 1936-circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Widlicka, Leopold, circa 1937-circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Wiencek, Alicia, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Wieseltheir, Vally, circa 1936-circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Wilenchick, Clement, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Wilks, Louis, circa 1936-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Williams, Frederick, circa 1936-circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Williams, J. Scott, circa 1920, circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 14)
    photos of Williams
  - Williams, Mildred E., 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Willis, Katharine, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Willmott, Cyril, 1937-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Wilson, John, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Wilson, Reginald, circa 1937-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Wilson, Sol, 1938-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Wiltz, A., circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Wingate, Arline, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Winograd, Ihann, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Winter, Andrew, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Wolff, Adolf, circa 1938-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Wolfson, A., 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Woodrum, V., 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Wooly, A., 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Wright, Mable, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Xceron, John, circa 1938-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 30)
    includes photos of Xceron, 1942
  - Xeneles, Phonnie, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Ximinez, A., circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - Yaghjian, Edmund K., 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - Yates, Ruth, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - Yorio, Pasquale, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - Yun, Tee, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - Yurchemo, Basel, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - Zaiden, Arthur, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - Zeitlin, Alexander, 1938-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 39)
  - Zemachson, Paul, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 40)
  - Zeigler, Lee Woodward, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 41)
  - Zilzer, Gyula, circa 1936-circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 42)
  - Zimmerman, Herman, 1938-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 43)
  - Zingale, Santos, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 44)
  - Zion, Ben, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 45)
  - Ziroli, Nicola Victor, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 46)
  - Zorach, William, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 47)
    includes photos of Zorach, Reginald Marsh and Louis Bouché; see also Subject Files, Art Week (Box 24, F16)
  - Zucker, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 48)
  - Zucker, Jacques, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 49)
- Subject Files, 1934-1956; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 2.8 Linear feet Boxes 25-32
  Photographs in this series document many of the FAP's educational activities, such as classes for children and adults, primarily in New York City, and active community and federal art centers in other states including Iowa, Florida, and Washington State. Also found here are photos of non-federal public buildings decorated with FAP artwork, such as airports; photos of artists at work and demonstrating various processes; photos of exhibitions, including some at the Harlem Art Center; photos documenting FAP branches, including the Easel Division, the Graphic Arts Division, and the Poster Division; and photos documenting the Federal Music, Theater and Writers' Projects. There is one folder of photographs of a Civilian Conservation Corps camps training school. Also found here are photographs of people and events, including FAP director, Holger Cahill, and various artists with their work in exhibitions
  One folder contains images taken by Berenice Abbott for the exhibition Changing New York, for the Museum of the City of New York in collaboration with the WPA.
  In addition to copy prints and scattered negatives the series also contains a transcript of a Signal Corps Photographic Center dedication.
  Photographs are arranged alphabetically by subject and folder title.
  - Airport Murals and Construction, Archival Resource Key (Box 25)
    - LaGuardia Airport, circa 1938-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Newark Airport, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - North Beach Airport, circa 1938-circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Armed Forces, circa 1939-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Art Centers, Community, Archival Resource Key (Box 25)
    - Iowa, Mason City, circa 1938-circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Iowa, Sioux City, circa 1937-circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Art Centers, Federal, Archival Resource Key (Box 25)
    - Arizona (Phoenix), circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Florida (Jacksonville, Miami, St. Petersburg), circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Montana (Butte), circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - New Mexico, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - North Carolina (Asheville, Greensboro, Raleigh?, Winston Salem), circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Ohio (Cleveland), circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Oklahoma (Oklahoma City, Tulsa), circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Tennessee (Norris), circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Virginia (Lynchburg), circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Art Week, circa 1940-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 16)
    includes photo of Reginald Marsh, and photo of Louis Bouche, Reginald Marsh, and William Zorach
  - Artists at Work, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Artists at Work, 1936-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 18)
    includes photos of Edward Laning
  - Building Exteriors, circa 1936-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Buildings with FAP Artwork, circa 1936-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Changing New York by Berenice Abbott, circa 1935-circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Children, circa 1935-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Children, 1935-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Children, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Children, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Civilian Conservation Corps Camps Training School, circa 1936-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Educational Exhibitions, Archival Resource Key (Box 26)
    - Chronic Disease, circa 1937-circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Visual Aid Objects for Defense, circa 1937-circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Why Plan Our City?, circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Lectures and Symposiums, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Metal Work-American, circa 1936-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Models, Interior, circa 1936-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Models, Miscellaneous, circa 1937-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Models, Naval and Military, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - New York City FAP Exhibitions, Archival Resource Key (Box 26)
    - Art Exhibitions, circa 1935-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Art Exhibitions, 1935-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Art Exhibitions, 1937 January-March; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Art Exhibitions, 1937 April-July; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Art Exhibitions, 1937 September-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 14)
      includes photos with Holger Cahill and others
    - Art Exhibitions, 1938 January-February; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Art Exhibitions, 1938 March-April; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Art Exhibitions, 1938 May; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Art Exhibitions, 1938 June-August; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Art Exhibitions, 1938 October-December; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Art Exhibitions, 1939-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Childrens' Exhibitions, Archival Resource Key (Box 27)
      - Exhibitions, circa 1936-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Exhibitions, 1935-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Exhibitions, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Exhibitions, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Exhibitions, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Childrens' Festival, Central Park, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Childrens' Festival, Central Park, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Harlem Art Center Exhibitions, circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 9)
      includes photos with William H. Johnson, Jacob Lawrence, Augusta Savage, and possibly Gwendolyn Knight
    - Students with Disabilities/Diseases, Exhibitions, circa 1937-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - New York City Federal Art Project Branches, Archival Resource Key (Box 27)
    - Design Laboratory, circa 1936-circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Easel Division, 1937, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Graphic Arts Division, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Home Design Workshops, 1938-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Motion Picture Production Unit, 1938-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Photographic Division, circa 1937-circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Photographic Division, Transcript of Signal Corps Photographic Center Dedication, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Poster Division, circa 1936-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Poster Division, circa 1936-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Poster Division, 1935-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Poster Division, 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Scenic Design and Model Making, circa 1936-circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Seamen's Institute, circa 1935-circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - New York City Free Art Classes, Archival Resource Key (Box 28)
    - Children at Work, circa 1935-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Children at Work, 1935-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Children at Work, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Children at Work, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Children at Work, 1938-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 11)
      includes photo of Louise Jefferson
    - Children at Work, 1940-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Childrens' Art, Archival Resource Key (Box 28)
      - Paintings, Murals, Lithographs, circa 1935-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - Paintings, Murals, Lithographs, 1935-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - Paintings, Murals, Lithographs, 1936-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Paintings, Murals, Lithographs, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Paintings, Murals, Lithographs, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Paintings, Murals, Lithographs, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Paintings, Murals, Lithographs, 1939-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Paintings, Murals, Lithographs, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Sculpture, circa 1935-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Sculpture, 1935-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - Sculpture, 1937-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - Sculpture, 1940-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Parent Classes, circa 1938-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Students at Work, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Students at Work, 1935-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Students at Work, 1939-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Other WPA Projects, Archival Resource Key (Box 29)
    - Federal Music Project, circa 1935-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Federal Theater Project, circa 1935-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Federal Writer's Project, circa 1936-circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Objective Teaching Materials Project, circa 1935-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - People Involved with FAP, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - People Involved with FAP, 1934-1945, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 20)
    includes photos with Gustave Baumann, Holger Cahill, Raymond Johnson, and Eugenie Shonnard
  - Processes, Archival Resource Key (Box 29)
    - Etching, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Fresco, circa 1935-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Lithography, circa 1937-circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Photography, circa 1935-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Sculpture, circa 1937-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Sculpture, circa 1937-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Sewing, circa 1935-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Silk Screen, circa 1935-circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Silk Screen, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Wood Engraving, circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Wood Working, circa 1935-circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Special Functions/Occasions, 1937-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 11)
    includes photos of Holger Cahill
  - Washington State FAP, Archival Resource Key (Box 30)
    - Art Galleries, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Artwork, Handicrafts, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Artwork, Models, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Artwork, Mosaics, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Artwork, Murals, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Artwork, Paintings and Drawings, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Artwork, Sculpture, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Interiors, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Men at Work, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - People, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 22)
      Includes photo of Holger Cahill and probably Dorothy Miller, also includes photo of WPA project staff in Seattle, Washington, circa 1936.
  - Workshop Interiors, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - World's Fair Buildings and Installations, circa 1938-circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - World's Fair Health Building, Leo Lance Gymnastics Mural, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified/Miscellaneous, Archival Resource Key (Box 31)
    - People and Places, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - People and Places, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - People and Places, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - People and Places, 1936-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - People and Places, 1938-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Photographs of Artwork, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of Artwork, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of Artwork, circa 1935-circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of Artwork, 1936-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 32, Folder 4)